Finding Aid for William Haber Papers, 1918-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Correspondence
  - Alphabetical series 1961-1965
    - U.S. Dept of Labor
      - Bureau of Employment Security
        - Goodwin, Robert C., Administrator (Box 10)
        - Summer Session Training Course (Box 10)
        - Federal Advisory Council on Employment Security (Box 10)
        - Unemployment Insurance Consultants (Box 10)
        - U.S. Employment Service, Louis Levine (Box 10)
      - Bureau of Labor Statistics (Box 10)
    - U.S. Dept of State (G. Mennen Williams) (Box 10)
    - Utah Dept of Employment Security (Box 10)
    - W miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - XYZ miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Zucker, Henry (Box 10)
  - Alphabetical series 1965-1966
    - A-B miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Boss, Mendel (Box 11)
    - C-H miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 11)
    - Haber, Frank (Box 11)
    - Haber, Ralph (Box 11)
    - Haber, Samuel (Box 11)
    - Haber, William (personal) (Box 11)
    - Heyns, Roger (Box 11)
    - I miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Irwin (Richard D. Irwin, Inc.) (Box 11)
    - J-K miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Kaphan, Gertrude (Box 11)
    - Kniaz, Esther-Itze (Box 11)
    - Knize, Leon (Box 11)
    - L miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Lamoreaux, David (Box 11)
    - M-N miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Nelson, Lyle (Box 11)
    - O-S miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Sachar, Abram (Box 12)
    - Shaban, Abel (Box 12)
    - T miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - U-V miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - U.S. Dept of Labor. Bureau of Employment Security (Box 12)
    - W miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - XYZ miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Zucker, Henry (Box 12)
  - Alphabetical series 1967-1978 (and earlier)
    - A miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Ackley, Gardner (Box 12)
    - American-Israel Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Inc. (Box 12)
    - American Israel Public Affairs Committee (Box 12)
    - Appleton, Shelley (Box 12)
    - B miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Bernhardt, Maurice (Box 12)
    - Bernstein, Phil (Box 12)
    - Bookstore (U-M) issue (Box 12)
    - Brener, Eleanor (Box 12)
    - C miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Cavanagh, Jerome P. (Box 13)
    - Clark, Peter (Box 13)
    - Cohen, Christopher (Box 13)
    - Cohen, Wilbur (Box 13)
    - Cohn, Irving I. (Box 13)
    - Cook, Thomas (Box 13)
    - D miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Dann, Sol (Box 13)
    - Dix, Samuel (Box 13)
    - E miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Esch, Marvin (Box 13)
    - F miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Fleming, Robben W., 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Freyman, Myer (Box 13)
    - G miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Ginsberg, Edward (Box 13)
    - Goldman, Gerald (Box 13)
    - Gordon, Jesse (Box 13)
    - H miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Haber, William
      - General (Box 13)
      - Oral history (Box 13)
      - Reviews (Box 13)
      - University of Michigan administration (Box 13)
    - Haifa University, American Friends of (Box 13)
    - Halpern, Frank (Box 13)
    - Halpern, Marcel (Box 13)
    - Hamilton, Jack (Box 13)
    - Handler, Milton (Box 14)
    - Hart, Philip (Box 14)
    - Harvard Center for Jewish Studies (Box 14)
    - Hatcher, Harlan (Box 14)
    - Heebink, David (Box 14)
    - Hexter, Maurice (Box 14)
    - Heyns, Roger (Box 14)
    - Hopkins, Clark (Box 14)
    - Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Interstate Conference of Employment Security Agencies (Box 14)
    - Irwin (Richard D. Irwin, Inc.) (Box 14)
    - J miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Jacobs, Irving (Box 14)
    - Jarrett, Jeffrey (Box 14)
    - Jewish Welfare Federation of Detroit (Box 14)
    - Judaic Studies Program 1970-1977 (Box 14)
    - K miscellaneous, 7 folders (Box 14)
    - Kane, Irving (Box 14)
    - Kaphan, Gertrude (Box 14)
    - Kasle, Abe and Leonard (Box 14)
    - Katone, George (Box 14)
    - Killingsworth, Charles (Box 14)
    - King, Sol (Box 14)
    - Kleinman, Shmarya (Box 14)
    - Klutznick, Philip (Box 14)
    - Kruger, Daniel, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - L miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Levin miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Levitan, Sar (Box 15)
    - Lown, Philip (Box 15)
    - M miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 15)
    - Michigan Employment Security Commission (Box 15)
    - Michigan Welfare League (Box 15)
    - Miller, Alex (Box 15)
    - Miller, James (Box 15)
    - Miller miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Milliken, William G. (Box 15)
    - Moss, John (Box 15)
    - N miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Nelson, Lyle (Box 15)
    - O miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Ohio Bureau of Employment Services (Box 15)
    - P miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 15)
    - Paper, Herbert (Box 15)
    - Parkes, David (Box 15)
    - Platt, John (Box 15)
    - R miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 15)
    - Raskas, Barach (Bernard) (Box 16)
    - Reinharz, Jehuda (Box 16)
    - Reuther (Walter, John, Victor) (Box 16)
    - Rhodes, Frank (Box 16)
    - Romney, George, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Ross, Arthur M. (Box 16)
    - Ryskamp, John (Box 16)
    - S miscellaneous, 7 folders (Box 16)
    - Schnitzer, Robert (and Marcella Cisney) (Box 16)
    - Schonfeld, ALice (Box 16)
    - Schwartz, Joseph (Box 16)
    - Shaban, Abel (and family) (Box 16)
    - Sharfman, I. Leo (and Minnie) (Box 16)
    - Shiffman, Abraham (Box 16)
    - Simons, Leonard (Box 16)
    - Slomovitz, Philip, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Smith, Allan, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Spivack, Joseph (Box 16)
    - Steiger, William (Box 16)
    - T miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - U-V miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - UAW (Box 16)
    - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare (Box 16)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - W miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Wallenberg (Raoul) Lectures (Box 17)
    - Winkelman, Stanley (Box 17)
    - Winter, Elmer (Box 17)
    - Woodcock, Leonard (Box 17)
    - XY miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Yeshiva University (Box 17)
    - Z miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Zucker, Henry L. (Box 17)
  - Alphabetical series 1979-1986 (and earlier)
    - A miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Ackley, Gardner (Box 17)
    - Anti-Defamation League (Box 17)
    - Appleton, Shelley (Box 17)
    - B miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Bernstein, Philip (Box 17)
    - Bernstein, Marver (Box 17)
    - C miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Cohen, Christopher (Box 17)
    - Cohen, Wilbur J. (Box 17)
    - Colen, Irma and Louis (Box 17)
    - D miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - E miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - F miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Fisher, Joel (Box 17)
    - Fleming, Robben (Box 17)
    - Freyman, Myer (Box 17)
    - Frimer, Norman E. (Box 17)
    - G miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Ginsberg, Sarah and Paul (Box 17)
    - H miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Haber, Alan (Box 18)
    - Haber, Frank (Box 18)
    - Haber, Michael (Box 18)
    - Haber, Ralph (Box 18)
    - Haber, Samuel, 11 folders (Box 18)
    - Haber, William
      - Personal (Box 18)
      - Oral history projects (Box 18)
      - William Haber chair (Box 18)
    - Halpern, Marcel and Frank (Box 19)
    - Heyns, Roger (Box 19)
    - I miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (Box 19)
    - J miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Jewish Welfare Federation of Detroit (Box 19)
    - Judaic Studies-Jewish History (Box 19)
    - K miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Kniaz various (Box 19)
    - L miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - M miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Michigan Employment Security Commission (Box 19)
    - Milliken, William (Box 19)
    - N-O miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - P miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Papier, William (Box 19)
    - R miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Recommendation (letters of) (Box 19)
    - S miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Shapiro, Harold (Box 19)
    - Slomovitz, Philip (Box 19)
    - T miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - U-V miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - UAW-AFL-CIO (Box 19)
    - University of Michigan general, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - W miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Wallenberg (Raoul) lectures (Box 20)
    - XYZ miscellaneous (Box 20)
- Jewish Organizations
  The Jewish Organizations (1941-1988; 10.5 linear feet) series consists of subseries of records maintained by Haber and documenting his extensive involvement in Jewish social action groups and educational institutions. Of special note are those files created while serving as Advisor on Jewish Affairs to the Commander-in-chief U.S. Forces in Germany and Austria (1948-1949). Included are various reports and memoranda, some correspondence, and notes he made relating to the issue of Palestine as a homeland for the Jews.
  The largest subseries in this series relate to his forty year relationship and activity with ORT (the Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training). Haber was a trusted advisor and a faithful correspondent with the leaders of this organization (of which he was one himself). His files are filled with communications about both the American ORT Federation and the World ORT Union. Although Haber was based in Ann Arbor, his files contain communications from throughout the world about the work of ORT and the condition of world Jewry. Of nearly the same bulk are the records from his activities with the Hillel Foundation of B'nai B'rith. As a respected educator, Haber was frequently asked to serve on various boards of educational institutions. Among these, Haber devoted most of this time to Hebrew University and Brandeis University. Smaller subseries in JEWISH ORGANIZATIONS include the American Jewish Committee, the American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, the Jewish Agency for Israel, and the Fund for Higher Education. For the researcher interested in any of these organizations, care should be taken to examine the CORRESPONDENCE series for the names of individuals closely associated with any given organization.
  - Miscellaneous 1948-1953 (Box 20)
    (include American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, United Service for New Americans)
  - National Refugee Service 1941-1942, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Advisor on Jewish Affairs to the Commander-in-chief U.S. Forces in Germany and Austria 1948-1949
    - Advisor's papers (reports, memoranda, etc.) 1946-1949, 4 folders (Box 20)
    - Notes on Palestine (Box 20)
    - Correspondence 1948 (arranged alphabetically), 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Correspondence 1949 (after return to the United States) (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training (ORT)
    - Yearbooks and Annual Reports 1951-1974 (American ORT Federation), 1 volumes (Box 20)
    - 1950-1960
      - General 1950-1955, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - General 1958-1960, 3 folders (Box 21)
        (no 1956-1957)
      - World ORT Union
        - Max Braude file (Box 21)
        - Daniel Mayer file (Box 21)
    - 1961-1965
      - American ORT Federation
        - General, 2 folders (Box 21)
        - Paul Bernick file, 3 folders (Box 21)
        - Earl Gilman file (Box 21)
        - Jack Rader file (Box 21)
        - Detroit Men's ORT Chapter (Box 21)
      - Canadian ORT Federation (Box 21)
      - World ORT Union
        - General, 2 folders (Box 21)
        - Rome conference 1965 (Box 21)
        - Max Braude file, 2 folders (Box 21)
        - Africa (Box 21)
        - Britain (Box 21)
        - France (Box 21)
        - India (Box 21)
        - Israel (Box 21)
        - Italy (Box 21)
        - Switzerland (Box 21)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
      - Women's American ORT
        - General, 2 folders (Box 21)
        - Nathan Gould file (Box 21)
      - Women's ORT Federation-Canadian (Box 21)
    - 1965-1966
      - William Haber personal (presidential address; clippings) (Box 22)
      - American ORT Federation
        - General (Box 22)
        - Paul Bernick file (Box 22)
        - Jack Rader file (Box 22)
        - Detroit Men's ORT Chapter (Box 22)
      - World ORT Union
        - General (Box 22)
        - Max Braude file (Box 22)
        - Africa (Box 22)
        - Britain (Box 22)
        - France (Box 22)
        - Israel (Box 22)
        - Italy (Box 22)
        - Switzerland (Box 22)
      - Women's American ORT
        - General (Box 22)
        - Nathan Gould file (Box 22)
    - 1966-1977
      - William Haber personal (clippings, speeches, etc.) (Box 22)
      - American ORT Federation
        - General, 8 folders (Box 22)
        - Paul Bernick file, 6 folders (Box 23)
        - Jack Rader file, 6 folders (Box 23)
        - Detroit Men's ORT Chapter, 2 folders (Box 23)
        - Overseas Study Mission 1968 (Box 23)
      - World ORT Union
        - General 1968-1977, 5 folders (Box 23)
        - Max Braude file, 2 folders (Box 23)
        - Max Braude file, 4 folders (Box 24)
        - Daniel Mayer file, 5 folders (Box 24)
        - Montreal Conference 1968 (Box 24)
        - 90th Anniversary Congress 1970 (Box 24)
        - Britain, 3 folders (Box 24)
        - Canada, 2 folders (Box 24)
        - France (Box 24)
        - Israel, 3 folders (Box 24)
        - India (Box 24)
        - Italy (Box 24)
        - South Africa (Freda Feldman) (Box 24)
        - South Africa, 3 folders (Box 24)
        - South America (Box 24)
      - Women's American ORT
        - General 1966-1970 (Box 24)
        - General 1971-1977, 3 folders (Box 25)
    - 1977-1986
      - Addresses of members (AOF; WOU) (Box 25)
      - Constitutions (AOF; WOU; Women's American ORT) (Box 25)
      - American ORT Federation
        - General, 6 folders (Box 25)
        - Paul Bernick file, 3 folders (Box 25)
        - Jack Rader file, 5 folders (Box 25)
        - Centennial Award to William Haber 1980 (Box 25)
        - Detroit Men's ORT Chapter (Box 25)
        - Engineers for ORT (Box 25)
        - ORTDATA (future of ORT) (Box 25)
      - World ORT Union (Box 26)
        - General, 6 folders (Box 26)
        - Max Braude file (Box 26)
        - Daniel Mayer file (Box 26)
        - Academic Advisory Council, 2 folders (Box 26)
        - Educational Study Mission 1983 (Box 26)
        - Technical Assistance Department (Box 26)
        - Max Braude ORT International School, Carmiel, Israel (Box 26)
        - Britain (Box 26)
        - Canada (Box 26)
        - Ethiopia 1978-1979 (Box 26)
        - France (Box 26)
        - Israel (Box 26)
        - Italy (Box 26)
        - South Africa (Freda Feldman) (Box 26)
        - South Africa (Box 26)
        - South America (Box 26)
      - Women's American ORT
        - General (Box 26)
        - Nathan Gould file (Box 26)
  - B'nai B'rith/Hillel Foundation
    - 1950-1959, 10 folders (Box 27)
    - 1956-1959
      - Sachar, A.L. (Box 27)
    - 1960 (alphabetically arranged), 27 folders
      (arranged by letter with individual folders for the following)
      - Bisgyer, Maurice (Box 27)
      - England (Box 27)
      - Jospe, Alfred (Box 27)
      - Kahn, Ben, 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Katz, Label A. (Box 27)
      - Klutznick, Philip (Box 27)
      - Shapiro, Judah (Box 27)
    - 1961-1965
      - General (Box 27)
      - Campuses (Box 27)
      - International Council (Box 27)
      - Bisgyer, Maurice (Box 27)
      - Goldberg, Saul (Box 27)
      - Gottschalk, Louis (Box 27)
      - Herzog, Myron (Box 27)
      - Jospe, Alfred (Box 27)
      - Kahn, Benjamin (Box 27)
      - Katz, Label (Box 27)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 28)
      - General (Box 28)
      - Campuses (Box 28)
      - Bisgyer, Maurice (Box 28)
      - Goldberg, Saul (Box 28)
      - Jospe, Alfred (Box 28)
      - Kahn, Benjamin (Box 28)
    - 1968-1977
      - General 1971-1973, 1975-1977, 4 folders (Box 28)
      - Ann Arbor 1971-1975, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Executive Committee, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Kahn, Benjamin, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Jospe, Alfred, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Frimer, Norman F. (Box 28)
      - Breira 1977, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Retirement Plans 1972-1977, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Special Committee on Dissent 1977, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Think-Tank 1975-1976 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous 1977, undated (Box 28)
    - 1978-1986 (Box 29)
      - General, 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Ann Arbor Board of Directors (Box 29)
      - Campuses (Box 29)
      - Frimer, Norman E. (Box 29)
      - Goldberg, Saul (Box 29)
      - Simon, Bernard (Box 29)
      - Nominating Committee for Chairman 1982-1983 (Box 29)
      - Retirement Board (Box 29)
      - Retirement Plans 1978 (Box 29)
  - American Jewish Committee
    - 1947 1949 (Box 29)
    - 1950-1952 (Box 29)
    - 1953-1962 (scattered) (Box 29)
    - 1970-1986, 7 folders (Box 29)
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee
    - 1958-1962 (Box 29)
    - 1965-1986, 6 folders (Box 29)
  - Jewish Agency for Israel 1973-1977, 8 folders (Box 30)
  - Fund for Higher Education (in Israel) 1971-1979, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Brandeis University
    - General 1963-1965, 1970-1985, 6 folders (Box 30)
    - Board of Trustees 1969-1970, 1974-1978, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Sachar, A.L. 1960-1962, 1967-1985, 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Schottland, Charles 1967-1972 (Box 30)
    - Bernstein, Marver 1971-1978, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Handler, Evelyn 1982-1986 (Box 30)
    - Honorary degree for William Haber 1975 (Box 30)
  - Hebrew University
    - General 1970-1986, 4 folders (Box 31)
    - Rothberg, Samuel 1975-1978, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - American Friends of Hebrew University
      - General 1953, 1963-1966, 1985, 5 folders (Box 31)
      - Academic Council 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Board of Governors 1979-1986 (Box 31)
      - Michigan chapter 1976-1986 (Box 31)
- University of Michigan
  The University 0f Michigan (1.5 linear feet) series consists of course materials for the various economics courses taught by William Haber, mainly on labor and collective bargaining. In addition, there are various chronological files and topical files relating to his career at the University of Michigan as teacher and advisor to President Robben Fleming. Files created in his capacity as Dean of the College of Literature, Science and the Arts have been maintained in that separate record group also housed at the Bentley Library.
  - Course materials
    - Economics 123 (also 23 and 423): Social Security (Box 31)
    - Economics 81a: Labor Problems (Box 31)
    - Economics 121 (also 421): Labor I (Box 31)
    - Economics 122 (also 422): Labor II (Box 31)
    - Economics 225: Labor Disputes (Box 31)
    - Economics 257 (Box 31)
    - Economics 305: Labor Conditions and Labor Problems (course books 1930 and 1931) (Box 31)
    - Economics 308: The State in Relation to Labor (course book) (Box 31)
    - Economics 322 (also 222): Collective Bargaining (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Dated Files 1936-1955 (scattered), 8 folders (Box 32)
  - Topical files 1960-1978
    - Admissions: Review Committee on Procedures 1962-1969, 3 folders (Box 32)
    - Affirmative Action (Box 32)
    - Chabad House 1976 (Box 32)
    - Consortium University (proposed) 1971-1973 (Box 32)
    - Extension Service
      - Unemployment Insurance Benefits Financing Course 1962 (Box 32)
      - Planning Study Committee for the Flint Campus 1969 (Box 32)
      - Planning Committee on Extension and Adult Education 1970, 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Re extension program and the U of M Flint and the U of M Dearborn 1972 (Box 32)
      - Committee on relationship between Extension Service and U of M Flint and U of M Dearborn 1974 (Box 32)
      - Ad hoc Committee on University Extension on the Branch Campuses 1975 (Box 32)
    - Honorary degree for President Ephraim Katzir of Israel 1975-1976 (Box 32)
    - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of 1976-1977 (Box 32)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Fund 1968-1970 (Box 32)
    - Opportunity Program Advisory Committee 1971-1972 (Box 32)
    - Promotions Procedures Review 1966-1970, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Students (Box 32)
    - University Calendar Committee 1960-1961 (Box 32)
- Other Organizational Activities
  Other Organizational Activities brings together the miscellanea of Haber's other career and civic interests. Here have been placed the files documenting Haber's work as administrator of the Michigan State Emergency Welfare Relief Administration. These files cover the period of 1933 to 1936. There are also files relating to his work with the National Resources Planning Board, 1940-1941. Of greater bulk (but still unprocessed) are the records of his service with the U.S. Bureau of Employment Security and the research undertaken with the W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research.
  - Michigan State Emergency Welfare Relief Administrator 1933-1936, 10 folders (Box 33)
    (include diary of activities)
  - Social Security Study Commission 1936-1939, 4 folders (Box 33)
  - National Resources Planning Board 1940-1941
    - Committee Members (Box 33)
    - Correspondence 1941 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence (by name)
      - Burns, Eveline (Box 33)
      - Delano Frederic A. (Box 33)
      - Eliot, Charles W. (Box 33)
      - Hoehler, Fred (Box 33)
      - Hunter, Howard (Box 33)
      - McClelland, Glenn B. (Box 33)
      - Somers, Herman (Box 33)
      - Stanchfield, Paul (Box 33)
      - Williams, Pierce (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33)
    - Personnel (Box 33)
  - Michigan Employment Security Commission. 1960-1961 (Box 33)
  - Unemployment compensation act revision 1963 (Box 33)
  - Batelle Memorial Institute 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Michigan Economic Action Council 1975-1978, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Michigan Manpower Commission 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - National Urban League 1954-1955 (Box 34)
  - Bureau of Employment Security (Box 34)
    unprocessed
  - W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research (Box 35)
  - W.E. Upjohn for Employment Research 1956-1961 (Box 36)
  - W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research (Box 37)
- Appearances
  The Appearances (1926-1984; 3.5 linear feet) series consists of the speeches and scholarly papers given by Haber over his long career. In addition, there are several folders of programs and announcements for William Haber speeches and appearances. Some of the materials in this series have been left in their original order within their folders; there is a great deal of overlap (for both organizations and dates) among the chronological folders, and they cover the years 1947-1974. There are also folders for individual organizations and appearances.
  - Speeches, conference presentations, etc.
    - Undated 1926-1936 (Box 37)
    - 1937-1961 (Box 38)
    - 1962-1984 (Box 39)
    - 1947-1960 undated (Box 40)
    - 1947-1971 undated (Box 40)
    - 1949-1971 undated (Box 40)
    - 1950-1963 undated (Box 40)
    - 1958-1974 undated (Box 40)
    - 1959-1974 undated (Box 40)
    - 1960-1968 undated (Box 40)
    - 1961-1978 undated (Box 40)
    - 1966-1976 undated (Box 40)
    - 1968-1980 undated (Box 40)
    - B'nai B'rith Hillel 1950-1968, undated (Box 40)
    - Hillel Kol Nidre Services October 7, 1962 (Box 40)
    - ORT
      - 1964-1965 undated (Box 40)
      - San Francisco Men's Chapter September 7, 1967 (Box 40)
    - ORT and B'nai B'rith 1969-1972, 1974, 1976-1979, undated (Box 40)
  - Programs, announcements, etc.
    - Undated, 1920s-1970s (Box 40)
    - 1980s (Box 41)
- Writings
  This series consists of reprints of writings, also book reviews written by Haber or book reviews of William Haber's books.
  - Reprints of writings (Box 41)
  - Book reviews written and reviews of WH books (Box 41)
  - Writings 1924, 1937, 1944, undated (Box 41)
- Scrapbooks, clippings, etc.
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases (Box 42)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases (Box 43)
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1928-1939 (Box 43)
    - 1934 (Box 43)
    - 1935 (Box 43)
    - 1936-1937 undated (Box 44)
    - 1937 (Box 44)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 44)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 44)
- Miscellaneous
  - Papers from the William Haber residence (Box 45)